Guide to the Director of Research files, [1905]1935-1965.
Director of Research files,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Director of Research files, [1905]1935-1965.
21-12-1074
New York State College of Agriculture. Director of Research.
8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection of correspondence, reports, research studies and committee reports for the Directors of Research, Department of Agriculture, primarily focused on the late 1950s to late 1960s with a small amount of documents from 1905 and the mid-1930s.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection of correspondence, reports, research studies and committee reports for the Directors of Research, Department of Agriculture, primarily focused on the late 1950s to late 1960s with a small amount of documents from 1905 and the mid-1930s.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; Cornell University -- Administration; Cornell University
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Departmental Programs and Areas of Interest
Series II. International Programs
Series III. Regional/N.Y State Programs
Series IV. Correspondence
Series V. Progress Reports and Research Reviews
Series VI. Department Committees and Reports
CONTAINER LIST
- Departmental Programs and Areas of Interest, 1950-1965
  - Agricultural Economics (1-3), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Oneida-Mohawk Region Dairy Study, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Engineering, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proposal for Dr. Leland Spencer, 1950-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agronomy (1), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agronomy (2), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agronomy Advisory Committee, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meterological Summary-Agronomy, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Animal Husbandry, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bailey Hortorium, 1964-965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Minutes #38, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Biochemistry, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Business Office, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Conservation (1-2), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Conservation Advisory Committee, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dairy and Food Science, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Entomology, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - J. P. Kramer, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - R. B. Root, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - R. D. Goeden, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - G. R. Stairs, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Extension-A.A. Johnson Director (1-2), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - State Leader's Office, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Distribution of Extension Bulletins (Director W. K. Kennedy), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dept. of Teaching and Information, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Farm Services and Student Practice, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Home Economics, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Home Economics College Council, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Home Economics Advisory Council, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - NY State Co-op Extension: "Organizaing for Program Implementation", 1964-02-02 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Plant Breeding, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Biometrics Unit (Plant Breeding), 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Plant Pathology, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Pomology, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Poultry Husbandry, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Resident Instruction - T.C. Watkins, Director, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Rural Education (1-2), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Rural Sociology, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Vegetable Crops, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Veterinary College, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- International Programs, 1961-1965
  - Philippines (Southwest Asia Program) (1-2), 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Annual Reports - Training Trainers in Comparative Extension Education, 1956-1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brazil, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chile, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Colombia Plan, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reports - Cornell Center for International Studies, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Tanganyika (East Africa Project), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ford Foundation Proposal, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - India (Indo-American Proposal-AID), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Philippines Development Program, 1962-07 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - International Grassland Congress, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - International Studies - Cornell (General), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - International Studies Bulletin, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - International Agricultural Development - Director K.L. Turk, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - IAD - Advisory Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - IAD - College of Agriculture (General), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Regional/New York State Programs, 1961-1965
  - Committee of Three, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cornell-Penn State Mtg, Wellsboro, Penn., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dean's Marketing Committee Report, 1965-04-06 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Experiment Station Committee on Organization and Policy (ESCOP) (1-2), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
  - ESCOP Legislative Committee (1-2), 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
  - Meeting in Lincoln, Nebraska, ESCOP Subcommittee on Marketing, 1950, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dedication of the Hudson Valley Research Lab, Poughkeepsie, NY., 1964-07-29 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Land-Grant College Meeting, Washington, DC., 1964-11-10 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Luncheon for Dr. George Mehren, Asst. Secy. Agr., 1965-01-18 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - N.Y.S. Management Institute, 1964-12-06-1964-12-11 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - NYS Soil Conservation Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Northeastern Corn Improvement Conference, 1964-02-19-1964-02-20 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Northeastern Agr. Exp. Sta. Directors Summer Meeting, Amherst, MA., 1964-08-09-1964-08-11 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Northeastern Directors, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Northeaster Directors Fall Meeting, Washington, DC., 1964-11-09 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Spring Meeting of the Northeastern Directors' Assoc., 1964-03-12-1964-03-13 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Northeast Directors' Questionnaire, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Patent Committee-Cornell Research Foundation, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - NYPAARC (Cornell - Penn St. Meeting), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Wellsboro, Pennsylvania (1), 1964-04-16-1964-04-17 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pennsylvania-Cornell Meeting, 1965-04-15-1965-04-17 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Statler Club Board of Directors, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Rural Area Development-Technical Action Panel, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - TAP Meeting to discuss North Country Drainage Proposal, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - SPICE State Poultry Industry Cooperative Effort, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - W.K. Kennedy: State Irrigation Research and Extension Project Prelim. Report, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Visit of Mr. Elwin W. Stevens, Asst VP Architecture and Planning, SUNY., 1965-05-26 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Temporary State Commission on Water Resource Planning, Conf. Report., 1964-12-11 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Annual CSRS Review, Cornell Expt. Station, 1962-06-04-1962-06-16 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Annual CSRS Review, Cornell Expt. Station, 1961-05-29-1961-06-10 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Annual CSRS Review, Cornell Expt. Station, 1960-06-06-1960-06-18 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Annual CSRS Review, Cornell Expt. Station, 1965-05-03-1965-05-07 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Review of Ag Engineering Research by the SESD, 1959-10-27-1959-10-29 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - USDA - SESD Summary of Current Program and Recs for Future Programs and Facilities, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - USDA Cooperative State Research Service, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Office of the Dean, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Agricultural Experiment Station, Geneva, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, 1958-1965
  Original files in loose alpha order, labelled "A, B, C, etc., with other files sometimes interspersed.
  - Agway, GLF, Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "B", 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - "C", 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - County Agricultural Agents, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "D", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "E", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "F", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "G", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Growth Chambers (1-3), 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence on Greenhouse and Growth Chamber, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Greenhouse and Growth Chamber, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Greenhouse and Growth Chamber, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Greenhouse and Growth Chamber 1963 (1-2), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Greenhouse and Growth Chamber, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "H", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Horse Census, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "I", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "J", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Director Valto Jarvi, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "K", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "L", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "M", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - "N", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "O", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "P", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Pesticides (Correspondence) (1), 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Pesticides (Correspondence) (2), 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Pesticides (Correspondence) (3), 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Includes corresp and reprints about Rachel Carson's "Silent Spring" and ensuing controversy.
  - President's Office and Provost's Office, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Controllers Office, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Treasurer's Office and University Counsel, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - "R", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - "S", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Wagner, R. E., 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Steward, F. C. - Director: Laboratory for Cell Physiology, Growth and Development, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - "T", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Texaco Research Laboratories, Poughkeepsie, 1965-02-15 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "U", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "V", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - "W", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - "XYZ", 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Unfiled Correspondence (1-3), 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 42-44)
- Progress Reports and Research Reviews, 1905, 1941-1965
  - Irrigation of Vegetables Progress Report, 1959-04-01-1959-11-15 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Reports of Agronomy, Plant and Conservation Depts., 1963-02-25 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Bioclimatic Lab - Greenhouses, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - US Soil, Plant and Nutrition Laboratory Dedication, 1963-05-31 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Regional Soil and Crop Management Program, Undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Facilities to Promote Research on Plant Nutrition and Metabolism in Relation to Growth and Development, 1960-08-25 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Addendum to Proposal: Facilities to Promote Research on Plant Nutrition and Metabolism in Relation to Growth and Development, 1960-09-23 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "Research at Cornell": 12th Annual Report of the Vice President of Research, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Expanding Basic Research in Bio Sciences, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Annual Changes to Research Programs, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Annual CSESS Review, 1963-06-17-1963-06-21 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Annual CSESS Review (1964) (1-2), 1964-04-06-1964-04-10 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Vegetable Crops Federal Comprehensive Review, 1905-05-15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - A Social Analysis of South Old Town, Long Island, 1962-10 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report of the Northeast Soil Research Committee, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Pesticide Residue Labs, Annual Reports (1), 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Pesticide Residue Labs, Annual Reports (2), 1956-1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Monsanto AID Cornell Research Project, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Annual CSRS Review Entomology, 1964-04-20-1964-04-24 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - CSESS Comprehensive Review, 1962-02 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Livestock Research Study (1-2), 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Food Research Program, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Forestry, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Agriculture in the United States, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Operation Advance (1-2), 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
  - Ornamental Horticulture Research Program, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Marketing - College Program, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Meat Animal Research Study Correspondence, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Long Island Vegetable Research Farm Report, 1959, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Long Island Vegetable Research Farm Report, 1960, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Research Projects Summaries, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Program Summary, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Design Manual Report Agronomy Building, 1964-08-19 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - United Fruit Equipment, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Progress Reports (1), 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Progress Reports (2), 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Progress Report 1964 (1-3), 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
  - Comprehensive Review, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Summaries of Outstanding Research Projects, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Hatch and State Summary Sheets, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Report of Interdepartmental Program for Plant Physiology (1964), 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Report of Interdepartmental Program for Plant Physiology (1963), 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Report of Interdepartmental Program for Plant Physiology (1962), 1962 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Report of Interdepartmental Program for Plant Physiology (1961), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Report of Interdepartmental Program for Plant Physiology (1960), 1960 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Report of Interdepartmental Program for Plant Physiology (1959), 1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Report of Interdepartmental Program for Plant Physiology (1958), 1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural College Council, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Research Projects - Geneva, 1933-1936 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Research - General, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Research Projects in Progress in the College of Home Econ., 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Federal Government Vouchers Form 1034 Revised, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - USDA Research Grant Fund Proposals, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Extension Projects (1), 1941-1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Extension Projects (2), 1949 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1955-56), 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1956-57), 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1958-59), 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1958-59), 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1959-60), 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1960-61), 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1961-62), 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1962-63), 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Analysis of State and Federal Research Projects (1963-64), 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Soil Survey, Tompkins County, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Proposal for a Program in Ecology (1-2), 1965 (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
  - Regional Research Materials and Reports: NEM 15, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Northeast Regional Project: NE 8, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Project Termination Reports, 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Pesticide-Related Research, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Regional Research Project: NEM 13, 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Northeast States Annual Reports, 1957-1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Northeast Regional Project: NE 22, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Research Grants Account (1-2), 1964-07-01-1965-06-30 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Department Committees and Reports, 1959-1965
  - Space Use Survey - forms, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Space Use Survey Govt. Sponsored Research, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Basic and Applied Research Calculations, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Expenditures - Sponsored Research, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - State Budget Request, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - State Budget Request, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - State Budget Request, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Budget Info: 1961-62 Agricultural Research Expenditures Ithaca and Geneva, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - College of Agriculture Budget Request for FY61-62, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - College of Agriculture Budget Request for FY62-63, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - CALS Budget, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Facilities and Equipment Expenditures, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Agriculture Faculty (1964-65), 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Agriculture Faculty (1962-63), 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Social Science Research Center Governing Board (1-2), 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
  - Faculty Research Grants Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Publications Committee - Home Economics, 1964-65, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Publications Committee - Home Economics, 1962-63, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Publications Committee - College of Agriculture, 1962-63, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Publications Committee - College of Agriculture, 1964-65, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - University Faculty, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Poultry Committees (1), 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Poultry Committees (2), 1960 (Box 8, Folder 27)